<chapter id="configuration"><title>Configuration</title>

<para>
</para>

<!-- ============================================================ -->
<sect1 id="config-display"><title>Display</title>
<!-- ============================================================ -->

<para>
  In the 'Display' dialog, you can control what is displayed when
  K-Meleon starts up, as well as what is displayed in any new windows
  you open (such as with Ctrl+N). You may also choose a background
  image for the toolbars, or disable the background image.
</para>

<figure><title><ulink type="http" url="images/Prefs_Display.png">Configure Display</ulink></title>
<graphic format="PNG" srccredit="pobelly" fileref="images/t_Prefs_Display"/>
</figure>


<variablelist>
<varlistentry><term>Home Page:</term>
<listitem>
<para>
</para>
<para>
  Your home page is the first page viewed when K-Meleon is started.
  A home page can either be an Internet web page or reside on a local
  hard drive.
</para>
<para>
  See the preference <link linkend='homePage'><varname>kmeleon.general.homePage</varname></link>.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>
<varlistentry><term>When K-Meleon starts, display:</term>
<listitem>
<para>
  Choose here whether to display a blank page, or the URL selected in
  'Home Page:' when K-Meleon first starts up.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>
<varlistentry><term>New windows should display:</term>
<listitem>
<para>
  Choose here what to display in new windows after K-Meleon starts
  up. You can choose to display a 'Blank Page', the 'Home Page', the
  'Current Page' of the old window, or you can choose 'URL' and
  specify any page you'd like.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>
<varlistentry><term>Toolbar Background Image</term>
<listitem>
<para>
  This is where you provide the path to a BMP file to be used for the
  background image for the toolbars, or uncheck the box to disable
  background images.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>
</variablelist>


</sect1>

<!-- ============================================================ -->
<sect1 id="config-general"><title>General</title>
<!-- ============================================================ -->

<para>
  In the 'General' dialog, you can control various behaviors of
  K-Meleon.
</para>

<figure><title><ulink type="http" url="images/Prefs_General.png">Configure General</ulink></title>
<graphic format="PNG" srccredit="pobelly" fileref="images/t_Prefs_General"/>
</figure>

<variablelist>
<varlistentry><term>View source with external command:</term>
<listitem>
<para>
  This is where you provide the path to a program (such as a text
  editor) that you would like to run when using the 'View Source'
  command, or you can leave the box unchecked to view the source in a
  K-Meleon window.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>
<varlistentry><term>Directories</term>
<listitem>
<para>
  You can specify here a directory path that you would like to use for
  your profile settings and for K-Meleon-specific plugins. For most
  purposes, you will want to leave these set to the defaults.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>
<varlistentry><term>Enhancements</term>
<listitem>
<para>
  Here you can check or uncheck boxes to enable or disable Java,
  Javascript, the 'Remember Passwords' feature, and the 'Allow all
  windows to be resized' feature. You can also specify what version of
  HTTP to use (1.1 by default).
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>
</variablelist>

</sect1>

<!-- ============================================================ -->
<sect1 id="config-privacy"><title>Privacy</title>
<!-- ============================================================ -->

<para>
  Many users want the ability to protect their privacy while using the
  Internet. K-Meleon includes a number of features designed to protect
  your privacy. These features allow you to set your own level of
  protection.
</para>

<figure><title><ulink type="http" url="images/Prefs_Privacy.png">Configure Privacy</ulink></title>
<graphic format="PNG" srccredit="pobelly" fileref="images/t_Prefs_Privacy"/>
</figure>

<para>
  K-Meleon provides these privacy features:
  <itemizedlist>
  <listitem><para>Browser Identification</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>Cookies</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>SSL</para></listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</para>

<!-- ............................................................ -->
<sect2 id="browser-identification"><title>Browser Identification</title>
<!-- ............................................................ -->

<para>
  When your browser accesses a web site, that site can capture
  information about you from your browser. Your browser identifies the
  browser and operating system that you are using through a reference
  called the UserAgent. You can change your browser indentification to
  help obscure your identity. Some users also change their browser
  identification to test browser-specific features of web sites or to
  ensure compatability with legacy scripts.
</para>

<para>
  The settings for Browser Indentification are located under Edit -
  Preferences - Privacy. K-Meleon includes 6 predefined UserAgent
  strings from you to select from. These settings are:
</para>

<para>
Identify browser as: selection Type of Browser/Operating System
Default Mozilla 0.9.5/Windows2000
Netscape 6.1 Netscape 6/6.1/WindowsNT
Netscape 4.76 Netscape 4.76/WindowsNT
MSIE 6.0 Internet Explorer 6/Windows2000
MSIE 5.5 Internet Explorer 5.5/WindowsNT
MSIE 4.0 Internet Explorer 4.0/WindowsNT
</para>

<para>
  To set your browser identification, select the browser
  identification you wish to use from the pull-down menu next to
  Identify browser as:. When you change the browser indentification
  from Default, the appropriate UserAgent string will be displayed in
  the UserAgent string: box. If you wish, you can further change this
  information by editing the information that is displayed in the
  box. Click on OK to save your changes. The UserAgent string
  associated with the Default is not displayed.
</para>


<note><para>
  Changing your UserAgent string from the Default will prevent JRE
  from working with your browser. Also, certain sites may not function
  or display properly if you change your UserAgent string.
</para></note>

</sect2>

<!-- ............................................................ -->
<sect2 id="cookies"><title>Cookies</title>
<!-- ............................................................ -->

<para>
  Cookies can be used to create profiles about you and your browsing
  habits and other personal information that you might not want to
  share with web sites that you visit. The ability to control cookies
  helps you protect your privacy. The settings for cookies are located
  under Edit - Preferences - Privacy. K-Meleon provides three levels
  of cookie acceptance. These settings are:
</para>

<para>
Setting Action
Accept all cookies Allows all cookies to be set and accessed regardless of their origin. This is the least secure setting.
Accept site cookies Allows only cookies to be set by the site that you are visiting. Cookies from other sites can not be set. This can help block cookies set by online advertisers.
Do not accept cookies Does not allow any cookies to be set. This is the most secure setting. It may prevent you from accessing some web sites.
</para>

<note><para>
  If you first allow cookies and then change your settings later to
  disallow cookies, sites may still be able to access your old
  cookies.
</para></note>

</sect2>

<!-- ............................................................ -->
<sect2 id="ssl"><title>SSL</title>
<!-- ............................................................ -->

<para>
  The Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol provides a way for a browser
  and a web site to authenticate each other and transmit encrypted
  information. This helps provide an additional layer of security when
  transmitting confidential data over the Internet. SSL is
  automatically enabled when you visit an encrypted site.
</para>

<para>
  K-Meleon also provides warnings when entering and leaving encrypted
  sites. You have the option of enabling or disabling these warnings
  from appearing when you visit encrypted sites. K-Meleon also
  provides a visual indicator of the level of encryption through the
  lock icon in the lower right-hand corner of the browser on the
  status bar.
</para>

<para>
Setting Action
There is NOT a secure connection with this site. Data transmitted to this site is not encrypted.
There is a secure connection with this site. Data transmitted to this site is encrypted.
</para>

</sect2>
</sect1>

<!-- ============================================================ -->
<sect1 id="config-cache"><title>Cache</title>
<!-- ============================================================ -->

<para>
  In the 'Cache' dialog, you can control how much space K-Meleon uses
  for storage of page content so that it doesn't need to be downloaded
  every time you view the page. You can set seperately the amount of
  space to use in memory and the amount of space to use on disk. You
  can also select a directory to be used for the storage, and how
  often the data in storage is refreshed with newer versions.  
</para>

<figure><title><ulink type="http" url="images/Prefs_Cache.png">Configure Cache</ulink></title>
<graphic format="PNG" srccredit="pobelly" fileref="images/t_Prefs_Cache"/>
</figure>

<variablelist>
<varlistentry><term>Cache Settings</term>
<listitem>
<para>
  Memory Cache: this is where you tell K-Meleon how much physical
  memory to use for storage of cached content; larger memory cache
  will improve performance, but you should make sure this number is
  not more than is likely to be available on your system. Setting this
  value to '0' (zero) may cause problems - don't do it.
</para>
<para>
  Disk Cache: this is where you tell K-Meleon how much space on your
  hard drive to use for storage of cached content; larger disk cache
  will reduce repeated downloading of more pages, providing faster
  page display on a slow connection. This number should be less than
  the amount of free space available on your drive. This value may be
  set to '0' (zero) if you don't want any content being cached to disk
  (for privacy or other reasons).
</para>
<para>
  Cache Directory: this is where you tell K-Meleon where you keep the
  cached content on your drive; the default setting is in your profile
  directory, which is suitable for most purposes.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>
<varlistentry><term>Cache Comparison</term>
<listitem>
<para>
  Cached data is compared to network data: this is where you tell
  K-Meleon how often to check for more recent versions of content in
  the cache; selecting 'Once per session' will enable checking for new
  versions every time you start up K-Meleon and begin browsing,
  selecting 'Always' will enable checking for new versions every time
  you visit a page, selecting 'Never' will disable checking for new
  versions of cached content ('offline' browsing), and selecting
  'Automatically' will cause K-Meleon to try to determine when cached
  data needs to be refreshed, and then do so.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>
</variablelist>


</sect1>

<!-- ============================================================ -->
<sect1 id="config-proxy"><title>Proxy</title>
<!-- ============================================================ -->

<para>
  Proxy servers are used in many organizations to provide access to
  the Internet. If you access the Internet through a proxy server,
  K-Meleon supports that connection. You also have the ability to
  exclude sites from the proxy server settings, allowing you to access
  those sites directly.
</para>

<figure><title><ulink type="http" url="images/Prefs_Proxy.png">Configure Proxy</ulink></title>
<graphic format="PNG" srccredit="pobelly" fileref="images/t_Prefs_Proxy"/>
</figure>

<!-- ............................................................ -->
<sect2 id="proxy-conf"><title>Configuration</title>
<!-- ............................................................ -->

<para>
  The settings for proxies are located under Edit - Preferences -
  Proxy. To enable proxies, select the option of Manual Proxy
  Settings. Enter the address of your proxy server next to the Proxy
  service that you wish to use. K-Meleon supports proxy settings for
  HTTP, FTP, SSL, Gopher and Socks v4 and v5. If you need to specify a
  port number for your proxy setting, enter it in the box labeled
  Port.
</para>

</sect2>

<!-- ............................................................ -->
<sect2 id="no-proxy-for"><title>No Proxy For</title>
<!-- ............................................................ -->

<para>
  In some cases, you may want to bypass your proxy settings to
  directly access a web site. K-Meleon allows you to enter exceptions
  to your proxy settings. Enter in the name(s) of the domain(s) that
  you want to access directly in the box labeled No Proxy For:. If you
  enter in multiple domain names, separate the domain names with
  commas. If you want to allow access to all sites within a single top
  level domain (TLD), like all .gov or .edu sites, enter in that TLD
  without any periods or wildcard characters.
</para>

</sect2>

<!-- ............................................................ -->
<sect2 id="automatic-proxy-conf"><title>Automatic Proxy Configuration URL</title>
<!-- ............................................................ -->

<para>
  To enable the Automatic Proxy Configuration, enter the URL for your
  PAC file in the box labeled Automatic proxy configuration URL.
</para>

</sect2>

<!-- ............................................................ -->
<sect2 id="http-version"><title>HTTP Version</title>
<!-- ............................................................ -->

<para>
  Some proxy products, like JunkBuster, don't support HTTP version
  1.1. You can change the HTTP version that K-Meleon uses under Edit -
  Preferences - General. Change the HTTP Version to 1.0 and click on
  OK.  
</para>

</sect2>
</sect1>

<!-- ============================================================ -->
<sect1 id="configs"><title>Configs</title>
<!-- ============================================================ -->

<para>
  Under the Configs tab you find all the configuration files that
  K-Meleon uses. Here you can configure all what can also be done from
  the other tabs, and a lot more. This is for the experts.
</para>

<figure><title><ulink type="http" url="images/Prefs_Configs.png">Configure Configs</ulink></title>
<graphic format="PNG" srccredit="pobelly" fileref="images/t_Prefs_Configs"/>
</figure>

<!-- ............................................................ -->
<sect2 id="config-menus"><title>Menus</title>
<!-- ............................................................ -->

<para>
</para>

</sect2>

<!-- ............................................................ -->
<sect2 id="config-accel"><title>Accelerators</title>
<!-- ............................................................ -->

<para>
</para>

</sect2>

<!-- ............................................................ -->
<sect2 id="config-prefs"><title>Prefs</title>
<!-- ............................................................ -->

<para>
  K-Meleon uses its own specific preferences as well as some from
  Mozilla. Many of these preferences can be accessed directly through
  the browser interface under Edit - Preferences. There are some
  preferences that are not directly accessible through the
  interface. In some cases, advanced users and administrators may want
  to control these preferences in order to modify the behavior of
  K-Meleon. Normally, all of K-Meleon's preferences are listed in the
  file prefs.js which can be accessed under Edit - Preferences -
  Configs - Prefs.
</para>

<para>
  Settings follow one of the following formats:
<programlisting>
  user_pref("Preference Name","string value");
  user_pref("Preference Name", numerical value);
  user_pref("Preference Name", boolean value);
</programlisting>
</para>

<note><para>
  It is often needed to restart K-Meleon to have the preferences added
  or modified reflected in K-Meleon.
</para></note>

<!-- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -  -->
<sect3 id="preference-references"><title>Preference References</title>
<!-- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -  -->

<para>
  Preferences used by K-Meleon include those specific to K-Meleon only
  and those that are defined by Mozilla. The following links list some
  of these preferences that are available for use.
</para>

<para>
  <itemizedlist>
  <listitem><para><link linkend="kmeleon-prefs">K-Meleon Specific Preferences</link></para></listitem>
  <listitem><para><link linkend="mozilla-prefs">Mozilla Preferences</link></para></listitem> 
  </itemizedlist>
</para>

</sect3>
</sect2>

<!-- ............................................................ -->
<sect2 id="config-macros"><title>Macros</title>
<!-- ............................................................ -->

<para>
</para>

</sect2>

<!-- ............................................................ -->
<sect2 id="config-toolbars"><title>Toolbars</title>
<!-- ............................................................ -->

<para>
</para>

</sect2>
</sect1>

<!-- ============================================================ -->
<sect1 id="config-plugins"><title>Plugins</title>
<!-- ============================================================ -->

<para>
  In the 'Plugins' dialog, you can control which K-Meleon-specific
  plugins are loaded when you start K-Meleon, and select options for
  some plugins.
</para>

<figure><title><ulink type="http" url="images/Prefs_Plugins.png">Configure Plugins</ulink></title>
<graphic format="PNG" srccredit="pobelly" fileref="images/t_Prefs_Plugins"/>
</figure>

<para>
  In the 'Plugins' dialog, you can control which K-Meleon-specific
  plugins are loaded when you start K-Meleon, and select options for
  some plugins.
</para>

<para>
The kplugins currently available in K-Meleon are:
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>Bitmapped Menus</para></listitem>
<listitem><para><link linkend='layers'>Layered Windows Plugin</link></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><link linkend='macros'>Macro Extension Plugin</link></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><link linkend='op-hotlist'>Opera Hotlis Plugin</link></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><link linkend='ie-favorites'>IE Favorites Plugin</link></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><link linkend='toolbars-cfg'>Toolbar Control Plugin</link></para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Rebar Menu Plugin</para></listitem>
<listitem><para><link linkend='ns-bookmarks'>Netscape Bookmark Plugin</link></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><link linkend='basic-history'>History Plugin</link></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><link linkend='basic-fullscreen'>Fullscreen Plugin</link></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><link linkend='external'>External Program Control Plugin</link></para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para>

<variablelist>
<varlistentry><term><guibutton>Configure...</guibutton></term>
<listitem>
<para>
  Clicking on this button will bring up an options
  dialog for the selected plugin, allowing you to change various
  aspects of it's behavior, or enable/disable certain of it's
  features. Note that not all plugins have options to configure.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>

<varlistentry><term><guibutton>Enable/Disable</guibutton></term>
<listitem>
<para>
  Clicking on this button will enable (checked box)
  or disable (unchecked box) the selected plugin. This determines
  whether or not the plugin will be loaded the next time you start
  K-Meleon.
</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>
</variablelist>

</sect1>

</chapter>
