<chapter id="getting-started"><title>Getting Started</title>

<!-- ============================================================ -->
<sect1 id="obtaining-kmeleon"><title>Obtaining K-Meleon</title>
<!-- ============================================================ -->

<para>
  K-Meleon is distributed as a single executable installer which will 
  extract all files.
  Download K-Meleon file from the homepage;
  <ulink type="http" url="http://kmeleon.sourceforge.net/download.php">http://kmeleon.sourceforge.net/download.php</ulink>.
  Select Full Package with Installer for version 0.7.
</para>

<para>
  When prompted, save the file onto your computer. Be sure to remember
  the download location that you selected.  
</para>

</sect1>

<!-- ============================================================ -->
<sect1 id="installation"><title>Installation</title>
<!-- ============================================================ -->

<para>
  If you have previously installed K-Meleon, make sure to uninstall
  the prior version before continuing the installation for this
  version.
</para>

<para>
  Go to the location where you saved the kmeleon06.exe file and
  double-click the file to start the Setup process. At any time in the
  process you need to stop the K-Meleon installation, click on the
  Cancel button.  
</para>

<para>
  When the License Agreement appears, read the license
  information. Click on Next to continue the installation.
</para>

<!-- ............................................................ -->
<sect2 id="installer"><title>K-Meleon Installer</title>
<!-- ............................................................ -->

<para>
  Setup next provides you with a list of Installation Options.   
</para>

<para>
  <itemizedlist>
  <listitem><para>K-Meleon (required)</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>K-Meleon loader (for faster startup times)</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>Standard Plugins</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>Bookmarks Plugin (for Netscape users)</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>IE Favorites (for IE users)</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>Opera Hotlist Plugin (for Opera users)</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>Start Menu and Desktop Icons</para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>Always open HTML with K-Meleon</para></listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</para>

<para>
  There are two types of installation Standard and Custom. In the
  Standard installation, most of the options are set to install or are
  enabled by default.  The Standard installation is selected by
  default. Most users will want to leave the Standard components and
  settings enabled 
</para>

<para>
  You also have the option of doing a Custom installation. Setup
  requires you to install the K-Meleon browser.  All other components
  and settings available through Setup are optional.  A description of
  some of the components is available in the FAQ. If you wish to
  remove a component through Setup, uncheck the box listed next to the
  option.  If you choose not to install a component, it can not be
  re-enabled in the browser so consider the impact of not selecting
  items. You can also disable components through the browser after it
  has been installed.
</para>

<para>
  When you have completed reviewing all of the components and
  settings, click on Next.
</para>

<para>
  Setup will indicate the location where it will install K-Meleon.
  Typically, it will install in C:\Program Files\K-Meleon.  If you
  would like to install K-Meleon in another location, use the Browse
  button to locate the directory where you would like K-Meleon
  installed. When you are ready to continue, click on Next.
</para>

<para>
  Setup will now copy over the necessary files for K-Meleon. A screen
  will display the files being copied onto your computer.
</para>

<para>
  When the installation process is completed, Setup will close and
  K-Meleon will launch to display a Read Me file. A short-cut for
  K-Meleon will also be available on your desktop, if you enabled that
  in the Installation Options.
</para>


</sect2>
</sect1>

<!-- ============================================================ -->
<sect1 id="running"><title>Running K-Meleon</title>
<!-- ============================================================ -->

<para> 
  K-Meleon can be started either by double clicking the icon on the
  desktop, or by selecting it from the start menu. (Look for the
  green lizard icon)
</para>

<!-- ............................................................ -->
<sect2 id="locate-bookmarks"><title>Locate bookmark files</title>
<!-- ............................................................ -->

<para>
  The first time you run K-Meleon you might be presented with one or
  two dialog boxes asking you questions.
  If you have installed the plugins for Netscape bookmarks or Opera
  hotlists you can decide whether to share your saved links between
  your earlier browser or start anew.
  K-Meleon can either create a new bookmarks or hotlist file or let
  you locate where your current file is.
</para>

<para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem>
  <para>
	Netscape bookmark plugin : "Bookmark file not found. Do you
	wish to locate it?"
  </para> 
  <para>
	If you have Netscape installed on your computer and you wish
	to be able to use your Netscape bookmarks in K-Meleon, you
	will need to click yes and find the bookmarks file. Otherwise
	click no, and K-Meleon will create a new bookmark file
	instead.
  </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
  <para>
	Opera Hotlist Plugin : "Would you like to set your hotlist file
	to the default value?"
  </para>
  <para>
	If you do not have Opera installed, and the following line is
	where you wish to store your Opera hotlist file, then click
	yes. Otherwise, if you wish to use your hotlist from Opera,
	you will need to click No, and locate the file.
  </para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para>

</sect2>

<!-- ............................................................ -->
<sect2 id="choose-profile"><title>Choose a profile</title>
<!-- ............................................................ -->

<para>
  The "Manage Profiles" window may also appear when starting K-Meleon
  after the first time.
</para>

<para>
  Profiles enable you to have different settings and configuration
  (like how K-Meleon looks and acts) as well as separate
  bookmarks/favorites/hotlist for the different users or people who
  may be using K-Meleon.
</para>

<para>
  You can use the new, rename and delete buttons to add, change or
  remove the names of the people who will be using K-Meleon. Then
  whenever K-Meleon starts the user would just click on his/her name,
  and then click ok to load K-Meleon with that user's settings.
</para>

<para>
  If however you don't want different settings for different users, or
  you are the only person that will be using K-Meleon, you can uncheck
  the "ask at startup" box, and then click Ok. This will prevent the
  profiles window from appearing at startup. You can still reach the
  profiles manager from within K-Meleon; under the Edit menu.
</para>

</sect2>

</sect1>


<!-- ============================================================ -->
<sect1 id="uninstall"><title>Uninstall</title>
<!-- ============================================================ -->

<orderedlist>
<listitem> 
  <para>
    Go to Settings - Control Panel - Add/Remove Programs
  </para>
</listitem>
<listitem> 
  <para>
    Select K-Meleon (remove only).
  </para>
</listitem>
<listitem> 
  <para>
    Click on the Add/Remove button.
  </para>
</listitem>
<listitem> 
  <para>
    The K-Meleon Uninstall program will prompt you with a confirmation
    before uninstalling K-Meleon.
  </para>
</listitem>
<listitem> 
  <para>
    If you have stored user profiles, the Uninstall program will
    prompt you if you want to remove the profiles.
  </para>
</listitem>
<listitem> 
  <para>
    Click on the Close button to close out the uninstall program when
    it is completed.
  </para>
</listitem>
</orderedlist>

</sect1>

</chapter>
