<chapter id="introduction"><title>Introduction</title>

<para>
  K-Meleon is a small web browser that embeds the NGLayout engine
  (also known as Gecko, the Mozilla rendering engine) by using the
  MfcEmbed components of Mozilla. K-Meleon is still under development
  and rather low on features right now. The design idea for K-Meleon
  is to be small and easy to use and configure. New features are added
  if they improve the performance and usefulness of the browser; not
  simply because they are "cool" to have. Whenever possible the extra
  funcitonality is added through plugins, which means that it will not
  be a burden for those who rather stay without. The modular design of
  K-Meleon is one of its strengths.
</para>

<para>
  K-Meleon is <emphasis>not</emphasis> a stripped down version of
  Netscape or Mozilla. It utilizes the same machinery to turn web
  pages into graphical views, but the rest is original work of the
  K-Meleon developers. Since K-Meleon implements a native Windows
  user interface it is lighter and faster (more responsive) than the
  Mozilla/Netscape/AOL browser, but it can only run on Microsoft
  Windows systems. This makes it a good choice for Windows computers
  close to, or even below, the minimum requirements for Mozilla. 
  Those who find the big browsers too big and that the other
  alternative browsers lack too much in standards complience are the
  intended audience for K-Meleon. People happy with their current
  browser seldom make good K-Meleon converts, as the gain from a
  lighter interface is much less with huge monster machines. No harm
  done if K-Meleon is not for you (or your friends). There is a
  browser for everyone.
</para>

<para>
  The, so called, "Browser War" is fought between big applications
  filled with features that require the very latest computer systems
  to run smoothly. It is flattering when people compare K-Meleon with
  those applications, but it is not needed. K-Meleon is not at war. 
  The K-Meleon developers do not aim for world domination. If you wish
  for all those add-ons, only remotedly related to
  <acronym>HTML</acronym> and Internet, you need more than a browser.
  K-Meleon has never been intended to become yet another "Internet
  Communication Suite". Just a mean and lean browsing machine.
</para>

<para>
</para>

<!-- ============================================================ -->
<sect1 id="kmeleon-homepage"><title>K-Meleon Home Page</title>
<!-- ============================================================ -->

<para>
  The K-Meleon project is hosted at SourceForge
  with a home page located at
  <ulink type="http" url="http://kmeleon.sourceforge.net">http://kmeleon.sourceforge.net</ulink>.
  (There is also a kmeleon.org domain that is supposed to redirect to
  the same machine, but unfortunately it has not worked flawlessly.)
  The home page is the main source for information about K-Meleon.
  At the home page you find download instructions, documents such as
  this manual and more targeted tutorials, resources like extra
  plugins and new skins, web-forums for discussions, and also a bug
  tracking system.
</para>

<!-- ............................................................ -->
<sect2 id="kmeleon-project"><title>K-Meleon Project Page</title>
<!-- ............................................................ -->

<para>
  At the <ulink type="http"
  url="http://sourceforge.net/projects/kmeleon">K-Meleon project page</ulink>
  you find online access to development related information; the
  developers mailing list and the CVS. If you wish to know what the
  developers discuss or what additions or bug-fixes have been worked
  on lately, this is the place to look at.
</para>

</sect2>
</sect1>

<!-- ============================================================ -->
<sect1 id="user-support"><title>User Support</title>
<!-- ============================================================ -->

<para>
  The user support offered by the kmeleon project is largely based on
  users helping each other. Developers partake in helping users when
  time permits.
</para>

<para>
  There are manuals, tutorials and references written both by
  developers and users. There are also open forums, like web-boards
  and mailing lists, where you can get answers to your specific
  questions by more experienced users. When you have solved your
  problem, please consider to submit a tutorial, or a clarification
  for the manual, that would have helped you solve your problem
  quicker. That is to some extent how the current help pages have been
  formed.
</para>

<!-- ............................................................ -->
<sect2 id="getting-help"><title>Getting Help</title>
<!-- ............................................................ -->

<para>
  The best help should help yourself to self-help.
</para>

<para>
  At the <ulink type="http"
  url="http://kmeleon.sourceforge.net/docs/index.php">documentation page</ulink>,
  we offer a set of shorter tutorials that will help you get started with
  some small, but commonly asked for, configuration tasks. There is
  also a list of <ulink type="http"
  url="http://kmeleon.sourceforge.net/docs/faq.php">Frequently Asked Questions</ulink>
  (with answers). Once you are a bit more aqcuainted with K-Meleon you
  should be able to digest the full manual. If you still cannot solve
  the problem you are very welcome to turn to the K-Meleon forum.
</para>

<tip>
<para>
  The forum is archived and it can therefore pay off to search among
  the old posts for questions similar to yours instead of posting the
  same question once more. This will save time, both for you and others.
</para>
</tip>


<!-- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -  -->
<sect3 id="web-forum"><title>The web forums</title>
<!-- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -  -->

<para>
  The <ulink type="http" url="http://kmeleon.sourceforge.net/forum/">
  K-Meleon web forum</ulink> is the place where users and developers
  meet to discuss problems in the current version as well as upcomming
  features and feature requests for future versions.
</para>

<para>
  Before you run off to ask questions at the web forum, grant us all
  some respect by acting as an intelligent human being. 
</para>

<para>
  You will look pretty silly if the issue is already mentioned, and
  solved, in the tutorials or FAQ. Always check there first.
  After that, see if you can solve the problem yourself from reading
  the manual. It is intended to include all information about the
  browser. Not all answers, but all information. You will have to
  apply the information on your problem to reach the answer.
</para>

<para>
  When you decide that you cannot solve the problem yourself but have
  to ask others for help, please remember that no one is obliged to
  help you. Be polite. Take the time to reread what you have written
  before you send it. Make sure it is clear what you want to achieve,
  what you have tried, and what goes wrong. If you cannot make
  yourself understood, or you come out as ignorant or demanding, you
  are not likely to receive much attention.
</para>

<para>
  A very good text about asking questions at open forums, where other
  people will help you without any compensation, is the text <ulink
  type="http" url="http://www.tuxedo.org/~esr/faqs/smart-questions.html"><citetitle>How 
  to Ask Questions The Smart Way</citetitle></ulink>, by Eric S. Raymond.
  Have you never thought of who will answer your questions and why,
  this is great food for thoughts.
</para>

<para>
  When you have become a more experienced user we would love to see
  you as a trouble-solver, helping new users. If you go for the real
  hard questions you might have to dig through the manual, use your
  full creativity, and learn something in the process yourself. In
  case you are not sure that you can give the correct answer you
  should avoid guess working. Perhaps you at least know what expert
  would be able to answer the question, and can help that way.
</para>

<para>
  It would be most useful if you point out what information in the
  manual could help the questioner find an answer himself. In the
  beginning it is not easy to answer your own questions with the use
  of a reference manual, but after a bit of practice everyone can do
  it. "Teach a man to fish..."
</para>

</sect3>
</sect2>

<!-- ............................................................ -->
<sect2 id="reporting-bugs"><title>Reporting Bugs</title>
<!-- ............................................................ -->

<para>
  If you think you have found something that might be a bug in
  K-Meleon, please start by taking a big breath and calm down.
  No one planted evil bugs in the program by will.
</para>

<para>
  Remember that not everything that acts like a bug is a bug. And not
  all bugs that affect K-Meleon are K-Meleon bugs. Sometimes it is a
  user error, somtimes it is an error in another program, and
  sometimes it really is a bug in K-Meleon. If you had any data losses
  due to the problem it is as sad no matter what the reason is.
  We understand your frustration and wish to help avoid that it ever
  happens again. Often we need your help to diagnose the error.
</para>

<para>
  When a site is not displaying properly it is normally caused by one
  of two issues. Either the site is not compliant with current HTML
  standards. It is the standards that tells how a browser should
  interpret correctly written web pages. When a page violates the
  standards there are no guarantess that all browsers will show it the
  same. Let the web masters know such errors. If the page is fully
  standards compliant the display problem is probably due to a bug, or
  missing features, in Mozilla.
</para>

<para>
  Before you start a big bug-hunting project try to find out if others
  have spotted the same behaviour before you. Search the bug tracking
  system and web board archives, or ask at one of the forums. If
  others have experienced the same issue as you they will tell you the
  current state of the problem. Sometimes this can be hints on how to
  work around it while waiting for the real fix.
</para>

<para>
  The key to understand what causes a malfunciton is being able to
  reproduce the faulty behaviour. Faults that only happens once in a
  blue moon are often extremely hard to fix. If your bug is mostly
  harmless it would be very helpful if you could try to provoke it a
  bit. Try to reproduced it. Write down the exact procedure to
  trigger the bug if you find out how.
</para>

<para>
  In case of application crashes you can use Dr.Watson to easily get
  an idea of where the problem happened. Never bother with the
  register dump from a blue screen, it is of no use at all. Search
  Dr.Watson's log file for the latest appended entry, and make sure it
  is K-Meleon. Write down what occurred. The comment on the exception
  is important, not the number. Note the function that has an entry
  marked with "FAULT". The function names in the Stack Back Trace for
  the faulting thread are very important too. Unfortunately K-Meleon
  is often stripped on debug information and symbol tables and thus
  shows entries like 'nosymobls'.
</para>

<para>
  With a bug you can reproduce, disable the plugins and see if the bug
  persits or goes away. Disbale most other options from the preference
  configure as well. Activate a few things at a time. Can you
  localize the error? Is it a specific plugin that causes the errors?
</para>

<para>
  Even if your bug is not fully reproducable but still happens now and
  then try to find any common factors for the times it does happen.
  What are you doing? How does the program respond?  Try to observe as
  much as possible that can help identify what goes wrong. 
</para>

<para>
  Writing a useful bug-report that leads to bugs being fixed is just
  as hard, if not harder, than posing questions that others care to
  answer. A good text to read before writing bug-reports is the text 
  <ulink type="http"
  url="http://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/bugs.html"><citetitle>How to
  Report Bugs Effectively</citetitle></ulink>, by Simon Tatham. Take some of those
  thoughts in consideration while writing your bug-report, and the bug
  might actually get fixed quicker.
</para>

<!-- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -  -->
<sect3 id="bts"><title>The Bug Tracking System</title>
<!-- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -  -->

<para>
  All bugs discovered and reported by users are kept in the bug
  tracking system. Before you report something as a bug, make sure it
  is truely a K-Meleon bug and that it is not already in the BTS. It
  is a good idea to discuss the issue with others at the web-forum
  first.
</para>

<note>
<para>
  Before you can enter your report you need to create an account with
  the K-Meleon Bug Tracking System. To do this you must pick a name
  and password as well as entering your e-mail address.
</para>
</note>

<para>
  When you write your report you should make sure it is easy to see
  already from the title what the bug is all about. Remeber to state
  what version of K-Meleon, and any other programs involved, that you
  use. Write the report in a way such that there are no doubts what
  one can do to reproduce the bug, what goes wrong for you, and what
  behaviour you expect to see instead. Write down any error messages
  verbatim.  Would you fail to express yourself clearly it is not
  likely that anyone can understand what goes wrong for you. There are
  too many bugs around to waste time on ghost hunts.
</para>

<para>
  If you feel like being helpful, you could take a look at the BTS and
  the current set of bugs. Several of the bugs are unconfirmed. Maybe
  you are the detective to decipher what the bug-report talk about and
  how one can reproduce the bug. Write a more clear comment in that
  case. There are sometimes open bugs that actually have been fixed
  already. Sometimes as a side effect from another bug fix or rewrite.
  Write a comment on what tests you did to come to the conclusion that
  the bug is no longer around.
</para>

</sect3>
</sect2>
</sect1>

<!-- ============================================================ -->
<sect1 id="development"><title>Development</title>
<!-- ============================================================ -->

<para>
  K-Meleon is developed as a Free Software / Open Source project. The
  full source code is available for everyone to download from the
  K-Meleon home page. Whoever feels that something is missing in the
  program is invited to help the project by adding that missing
  piece. All developers are volunteers, working on the parts they care
  for. The work is done during spare-time. No one is payed to work on
  this project.
</para>

<para>
  Bug Reports and Requests For Enhancements are accepted, but since
  developers first work on the parts they feel are the most important
  or interesting themselves, it might take a while before your issue
  is addressed by anyone. If a bug gives you an itchy feeling you are
  more than welcome to start scratch. Once you are done everyone will
  benefit from it.
</para>

<para>
  Development of an application is, of course, not only about writing
  source code. It is as much about writing documentation, testing new
  builds, finding new bugs, house-keeping the bug tracking system, and
  creating art works. This makes every user a potential developer!
</para>

<para>
  Please consider to contribute to the kmeleon project.
</para>

<!-- ............................................................ -->
<sect2 id="cvs"><title>CVS</title>
<!-- ............................................................ -->

<para>
  The full source of K-Meleon is kept in a versioning systen at a
  central server. The CVS repository is world readable, but only the
  developers have write access to it. You can check-out any revision
  from it (not only full versions), and you can see the changes made
  each time. For the curious without a CVS client there is a web
  interface to the CVS accessable from the K-Meleon project page.
</para>

</sect2>

<!-- ............................................................ -->
<sect2 id="kmeleon-dev"><title>kmeleon-dev Mailing List</title>
<!-- ............................................................ -->

<para>
  All developers gather around the <ulink
  url="http://lists.sourceforge.net/lists/listinfo/kmeleon-dev">kmeleon-dev
  mailing list</ulink> to discuss and coordinate their work. Everyone
  interested may join, not only developers. For new developers the
  mailing list is the place to ask for help while trying to add new
  ideas or squash old bugs.
</para>

</sect2>
</sect1>

<!-- ============================================================ -->
<sect1 id="copyright"><title>Copyright</title>
<!-- ============================================================ -->

<para>
  K-Meleon is Copyright (C) 2000-2002 the kmeleon.org project.
</para>

<para>
  This program is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify
  it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by
  the Free Software Foundation; either version 2 of the License, or
  (at your option) any later version.
</para>

<para>
  This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but
  WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
  MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the GNU
  General Public License for more details.
</para>

<para>
  You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
  along with this program; if not, write to the Free Software
  Foundation, Inc., 59 Temple Place - Suite 330, Boston, MA 02111,
  USA.
</para>

</sect1>

</chapter>
